Purushothama Raju Prathigudupu (1) Featured



Consultant seeking roles as SAP ABAP Developer. Proficient in Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management & Requirement Gathering. Have knowledge in Android App Development, Machine Learning, Python, **HTML & Bootstrap**



Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Consultant

Current Company: Deloitte Consulting India Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: SAP ABAP, Adobe Forms, SAP Workflow, IDOCS, BADIs, Android Application Development, SQL, Machine

Learning, Python, HTML, Bootstrap, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality

Management & Requirement Gathering

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

I'm a highly competent professional with 6+ years of experience in SAP ABAP. Self-starter and quick learner who always exceeds expectations. Equipped with a record of success in consistently delivering quality work with a quick turnaround.

Proficient in developing Reports, Adobe forms, Enhancements, Routines, troubleshooting simple/complex issues and optimizing code for performance improvement.

I love coding!! Not just SAP ABAP, I like exploring all other technologies too.

Work Experience

Deloitte Consulting India Pvt. Ltd as Consultant

Feb 2018 to Till Date

Had been promoted as Consultant from Business Technology Analyst after just a year of joining.

Developed a Utility Report that notifies the Developers whenever their Transports get released to further landscapes (Quality/Production), which reduces manual efforts to check the Transport Logs every single day.

Worked on a Finance Project which involved calling an External API provided by a bank to validate the Master Data changes.

Created an RF compatible program to reverse the Goods Receipt of Pack Order and its linked Bulk Orders based on Sequence No.

Developed a program to generate the Annual Mailer Letters by displaying content from the Standard Text with dynamic values and formatting the style of the text using Smart Styles while displaying on Adobe forms. This allowed the business users to change the content every year directly in the Standard Text, without the need of making any changes in the Program or Adobe form every year.

Provided a solution to reduce those manual efforts and automated the update of Profit Center prior to processing the payments, before which Finance Team used to execute a custom transaction daily and check for errors on Profit Center to re-process them by updating the Profit Center manually. This saved lot of manual efforts for Finance Team.

Created a Dashboard in Service-Now that shows the Statistics and Active Tickets for the Entire Team, which is used by Managers during our Weekly Team Meeting to keep track of the Team's work.

Had setup On-call Scheduling in Service-Now to automate the process of preparing Roster and sending Reminder emails to the Primary and Secondary Contact Resources every week, which used to be done manually earlier.

Tech Mahindra as Software Engineer

Aug 2014 to Jan 2018

Started career as SAP ABAP Developer and had worked with a Client from Chemical Industry.

IDocs gets generated with Payment Run with the Payment Method "Cheque". Developed a report to get the IDoc details and generate Data and Control files (Needed to Out-source the checks) that gets stored in the application server, which will be sent to the Bank via WebMethods.

Implemented notes to generate Hungarian Audit Report and have done some customization to the Invoice details in that report using User-Exits as per customer's requirement.

A Custom Report exists to post Accounting Documents by pulling the expense reports from the Extract file generated in Concur (Third-Party Expense Management Application) via WebMethods. Enhanced this report to post documents for Credit Card & Purchase Card Expenses along with Out-Of-Pocket Expenses including VAT details handling Taxation based on region.

Acted as Concur Administrator and provided support for Customers for issues with payments or new user setup.

Developed a Custom Program to get the Payroll file (from WorkDay HR system) pushed into the application server and post the Journal entries to get the payment done. Also, added the functionality to send the error documents as Fallouts, and to trigger an email regarding this error, which helps the authorized person to fix the errors in the document and reprocess it.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Bapatla Engineering College, bapatla in 2014

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Machine Learning Online course

Bootstrap Web UI Framework - Online course

SAP ABAP on HANA

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
sap abap	7.31	2020	6 Year(s) 3 Month(s)	
CoreJava	13	2020	5 Month(s)	
Android App Development	7	2016	4 Month(s)	
HTML	5	2020	4 Month(s)	
BOOTSTRAP	4	2020	3 Month(s)	
Python	3	2020	6 Month(s)	
SAP Concur	2017	2017	1 Year(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=3d8ff4fd85ba69daf8bdb2c8ab31784e50095b554b115b110316420e540...

Hindi	Proficient	
Telugu	Expert	
Tamil	Proficient	

Projects

Project Title: Dairy Farmers of America Client: Dairy Farmers of America Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 18

Skill Used: SAP ABAP, Reports, Adone forms, SAP Workflow, IDOCS, Badis, User Exits, Enhancements

Role Description: Worked as a Consultant at Deloitte, helping the client with their requirements

Project Details: Dairy Farmers of America is a leading Milk Industry in USA. I am part of the development team that supports

Duration: Feb 2018 - Dec 2020

the client to mange their business through SAP.

Project Title: Solenis Client: Solenis

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2014 - Jan 2018
Project Location: Chennai & Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 20 Skill Used: SAP ABAP, Reports, Smartforms, SAP Scripts, User Exits, Enhancements

Role Description: Supported the client while working on new requirements and with many customizations in their processes

to reduce their manual efforts.

Project Details: Solenis is a supplier of water treatment and processing chemicals. They were using SAP to reduce human

efforts by integrating their tasks with SAP.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time